Guide to the Newspaper clippings on Ferdinand Marcos and Corazon Aquino, 1986-1987.
Newspaper clippings on Ferdinand Marcos and Corazon Aquino
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Newspaper clippings on Ferdinand Marcos and Corazon Aquino, 1986-1987.
8563
0.3 cubic feet.
Newspapers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Clippings from Philippine and United States newspapers, together with 3 magazine articles. Newspapers include the New York times, Philippine star, People's journal, Philippine daily inquirer, Manila evening post, Los Angeles times, and others.
Corazon Aquino succeeded Ferdinand Marcos as president of the Philippines in 1986.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Clippings from Philippine and United States newspapers, together with 3 magazine articles. Newspapers include the New York times, Philippine star, People's journal, Philippine daily inquirer, Manila evening post, Los Angeles times, and others.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Aquino, Corazon Cojuangco.; Marcos, Ferdinand E. (Ferdinand Edralin), 1917-1989.
Subjects:
Press and politics -- Philippines.
Places:
Philippines -- Politics and government -- 1973-1986.; Philippines -- Politics and government -- 1986-
Form and Genre Terms:
Clippings (information artifacts)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Marcos Record, Febraury 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  KBL (Kilusang Bagong Lipunan), pro-Marcos political pamphlet
- People magazine, March 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Article on Marcos' assets
- Asiaweek, March 16, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  pp. 12-24, cover story: "A Huge Job - the Challenges Ahead for Aquino"
- Veritas Newsmagazine, Vol. Ill no. 17, March 9, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Cover story: "Uneasy Alliance: To Work Within Marcos' Laws or Not: Cory Aquino's Dilemma"
- Parade, Sunday newspaper magazine, June 8, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Cover story: "The Passage of Corazon Aquino" by Gail Sheehy; cover page photo and pp. 4-10
- San Francisco Examiner, January 26, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Story: "Aquino tapes called a ruse to soothe U.S."
- Los Angeles Times, January 26, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  pp. 1-6, story: "Manila on Edge: Marcos Return, Coups Rumored"
- New York Times, Vol. CXXXVI no. 47,031, January 26, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  pp. 1-2 only, story: "Test for Aquino: Will the Center Hold?"
- San Francisco Chronicle, January 26, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  pp. 11-14 only, story: "Land Issue May Be Aquino's Achilles Heel"
- Malaya, the People's National Newspaper, Vol. VI no. 12, January 28, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  pp. 1-8, headline: "Rebellion Crushed: Aquino orders punishment of military rebels"
- Malaya,the People's National Newspaper, Charter supplement, supplement to Vol. VI no. 12, January 28, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Headline: "The vision of the 1986 draft Constitution"
- Philippine Daily Inquirer, Vol. 2 no. 50, January 28, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  pp. 1-6, headline: "Surrender or Else: Cory's Ultimatum to Rebel Troops"
- Manila Chronicle, Vol. XXX no. 28, January 28, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Headline: "Plotters Identified, Face Court Martial"
- People's Journal, Everybody's Newspaper, January 28, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  pp. 1-8, cover story: "Tit for Tat: Attack Channel 7 - Cory"
- Philippine Star, Vol. 1 no. 157, January 28, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  pp. 1-4, headline: "Court Martial for Plotters"; stories continued on p. 6, not included in clippings
- Manila Evening Post, Vol. XI, no. 190, January 28, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  pp. 1-4, headline: "Soldiers Holding On, Set Forth 5 Demands"; stories continued on p. 8, not included in clippings
- Manila Chronicle, January 28, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  pp. 9-10 only, story: "Public outrage on Mendiola massacre"
- People's Journal Tonight, January 28, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  pp. 1-4 only, headline: "Last Chance to Surrender"
- Philippine Star, Vol. 1 no. 158, January 29, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Headline: "Assault Called Off: Talks resume after gas attack"
- Manila Bulletin, Vol. 169 no. 29, January 29, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  pp. 1-2 only, headline: "Ramos submits coup plotters' list", stories continued on pp. 10 and 14, not included in clippings
- People's Journal, Everybody's Newspaper, January 29, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  pp. 1-6, headline: "Cebu Alert for Marcos"
- People's Journal Tonight, January 29, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  pp. 1-2, headline: "Soldiers Won't Fire on Soldiers"
- Philippine Daily Inquirer, Vol. 2 no. 51, January 29, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  pp. 1-8, headline: "GMA-7 standoff drags on"
- Manila Times, Vol. XXIX no. 29, January 29, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Headline: "Rebel soldiers tear­gassed"
- MidDay, Vol. 1 no. 287, January 29, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  pp. 1-6, headline: "Mutineers Surrender"
- Philippine Daily Inquirer, Vol. 2 no. 52, January 30, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  pp. 1-4, headline: "F.M. [Ferdinand Marcos] Return Foiled"; stories continued on p. 6, not included in clippings
- Manila Evening Post, Vol. XI no. 192, January 30, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  pp. 1-2, headline: "Doublecross Seen in Handling Rebs"; stories continue on p. 9, not included in clippings
- Manila Evening Post, Vol. XI no. 194, February 2, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  pp. 1-2, headline: "Voters' Turnout Heavy; Minor Confusion Noted"; stories continued on p. 9, not included in clippings
- Veritas Magazine, Vol. IV no. 10, January 29-February 4, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Cover story: "The Troubled Week: Events that Shook the Cory Government"